<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Weijun&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://weijun-h.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Weijun&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 18:18:51 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://weijun-h.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 2 - Construct Regression functions in queries with GROUP BY</title>
      <link>https://weijun-h.github.io/posts/gsoc_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 18:18:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://weijun-h.github.io/posts/gsoc_02/</guid>
      <description>Overview In this week
Design What should I do next step?  How window function works in queries Add more tests with edge cases  graph TD; A--B; A--C; B--D; C--D;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Week 1 - Explore the Mechanism in MariaDB</title>
      <link>https://weijun-h.github.io/posts/gsoc_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 19:53:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://weijun-h.github.io/posts/gsoc_01/</guid>
      <description>Overview My task is to implement regression functions in MariaDB, which was mentioned in MDEV-17467. This feature has been implemented by many MariaDB competitors, like PostgreSQL, Oracle, and so on.
Tasks The functions I need to implement are following:
 REGR_SLOPE: Returns the slope, equal to REGR_SXY / REGR_SYY REGR_INTERCEPT: Returns the y-intercept of the regression line, which is equal to REGR_AVGX - REGR_SLOPE * REGR_AVGY REGR_COUNT: Returns the number of non-empty pairs of numbers used to fill the regression line REGR_R2: The return value is equal to (REGR_SXY * REGR_SXY) / (REGR_SYY * REGR_SXX) REGR_AVGX: calculate the mean of the independent variable (expr2) of the regression line, after removing the null pair (expr1, expr2), is equal to AVG(expr2) REGR_AVGY: Calculate the mean of the strain variable (expr1) of the regression line, after removing the null pair (expr1, expr2), which is equal to AVG(expr1) REGR_SXX: The return value is equal to REGR_COUNT * VAR_POP(expr2) REGR_SYY: The return value is equal to REGR_COUNT * VAR_POP(expr1) REGR_SXY: The return value is equal to REGR_COUNT * COVAR_POP(expr1, expr2)  Mechanism How to define a function in MariaDB For native functions, it is easy to define.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
